

WEB DEVELOPER

5 Brown Ave, Roslindale, MA, 02131 ieloletin@gmail.com 419.360.2989

SUMMARY: Whether creating full-stack web applications, treating and transporting people having medical emergencies or building and maintaining aquatic exhibits, I am experienced in meeting goals under strict deadlines. I am driven and dedicated to creating products that are practical, functional tools which help simplify people's lives.

Experience

Dana-Farber Cancer Institute / Web Developer

May 2017 - Present | Boston, MA

- Created an Angular 5 frontend for an existing production application
- ➤ Utilized Angular 5 to create features for a v1 production application
- > Participated in weekly code reviews

Dana-Farber Cancer Institute / Web Developer Intern

March 2017 - May 2017 | Boston, MA

- Created an Angular 4 proof of concept application with a small team
- Utilized Spring Boot to create RESTful API endpoints
- > Created documentation for a web application proof of concept
- Collaborated with other developers in an Agile workflow
- Utilized GitLab for version control

General Assembly / Full-Stack Web Developer in Training

October 2016 - January 2017 | Boston, MA

Built full-stack applications during a 12-week web development immersive, by creating and utilizing:

- > RESTful APIs and single-page applications
- Version Control (Git and GitHub)
- User Stories, Wireframes and ERDs
- Pair programming, working as part of a team and individual coding

Job Experience

Boston EMS / Emergency Medical Technician

January 2014 - October 2016 | Boston, MA

- Responded to emergency calls placed via the 9-1-1 system.
- Assessed and treated the diverse population of Boston citizens, according to local and state protocols, including administering medications.
- > Transported patients to local hospitals.
- > Documented care provided to patients and communicated pertinent information to hospital staff.

New England Aquarium / Aquarist

February 2010 - January 2014 | Boston, MA

- > Provided animal husbandry for marine and freshwater organisms.
- > Maintained life support systems and aquatic environmental parameters.
- > Interviewed, hired, trained and supervised volunteers and interns.

Skills		
Angular	CSS	JavaScript
Handlebars	Ruby	Ruby on Rails
JQuery	SQL	PostgreSQL
Express.js	Git	Ember.js
Bootstrap	SCSS	MongoDB
Node.js	AJAX	Mongoose
Spring Boot	Java	HTML

Education

Northeastern University 2009

Boston, MA

Bachelors of Science: Biology

Code Samples

Portfolio: ariel-n-martin.com

GitHub: github.com/ielole

Interests

- Reading
- SCUBA diving
- Rock Climbing
- Black and White Photography
 - Sustainable Energy
 - Conservation